# 福建 泉州（地名）
(Quanzhou, Fujian)
# 今天我们要去买芋头饼
# 福建 泉州（地名）
Today, we're going to buy some taro cakes.
(Quanzhou, Fujian)
# 虽然说 阿姨是从5点开始卖
Even though the auntie starts selling at 5 o'clock,
# 但在从4点开始
starting from 4 o'clock,
# 已经有很多的人在这边排队
there're already a lot of people lining up.
# 现在是4点半
It's 4:30 right now,
# 这边排起了一个小长龙
and we already got quite a long line here.
# （等）
(Waiting...)
# （接着等）
(Keep waiting...)
# 其实站在这个位置
Standing at this position of the line,
# 我真的担心会买不上
I'm worried if I can get one.
# （队伍更长了）
(The line is even longer)
# （载过来的芋头饼）
(Taro cakes are carried here)
# （卖的很快）
(And they are sold out fast)
# （排队买）
(Lining up to buy)
# 这样7个（芋头饼）
Here's 7 cakes.
# 7... 7... 乘以 3.5 （原字幕没有）
7... 7... times 3.5...
# 一共是24.5块钱
24.5 yuan.
# 来 放这边（原字幕没有）
I'll put it here.
# 42，对（原字幕没有）
42 yuan, right.
# （微信收款 42元）
(WeChat payment received, 42 yuan)
# 阿姨 只有两种口味是吧（嗯嗯）
Are there only two flavors, auntie? (Yes)
# 甜的和咸的（嗯）
Sweet and salty? (Yes)
# 给我各拿3个吧
I'll have three of them each.
# 3个
Three cakes.
# 3个是多少钱？呃 6个
How much are three cakes? 6 cakes, actually.
# 21块钱
21 yuan.
# （微信收款）
(WeChat payment received)
# （7元）
(7 yuan)
# 这个芋头饼刚买来的时候
When we just got the taro cakes,
# 它还是有点温热的
they were still a little hot.
# 不过 现在已经不算很热的
Now, they are not that hot already.
# 她这边是分甜的和咸的口味
There are sweet and salty flavors.
# 3块5一个
3.5 yuan each.
# 用黑芝麻和白芝麻来作为区分
Marked differently with black or white sesame.
# 芋头饼就是
Their taro cakes...
# 两个饼干 中间夹了馅
are like two cakes with stuffing in the middle.
# 上面应该是裹了一些面糊 炸出来的
Possibly coated with some fried starch coating.
# 我也不知道哪个是甜的 哪个是咸的
I don't know which one is sweet or salty.
# 咱们先看看这个
Let's check this one first,
# 白芝麻是什么样的口味
the one with white sesame.
# 中间是芋泥
There's mashed taro in the middle.
# 甜的
It's sweet.
# 其实这个芋头饼一口咬下去
Actually, with a bite in this taro cake,
# 它外面的（饼干）还带有脆口的感觉
you may find the cake kind of crispy.
# 但这个芋泥 真的是
However, the mashed taro
# 既厚实 又绵软
is both thick and mashy.
# 它这个甜度刚好 不至于很甜
It has just the right level of sweetness,
# 让人觉得腻 觉得齁
so you don't feel greasy or cloying.
# 因为它上面加了一些白芝麻
As there's some white sesame,
# 白芝麻的香味还是比较浓重的
the aroma of white sesame is quite obvious.
# 增加了一些香味
So the overall smell is enhanced.
3 它其实这个 咸味的芋头饼
Speaking of this salty taro cake,
# 只不过是把刚才的甜口换成咸口
it's simply changing the sweet flavor of the last one into a salty flavor.
# 依然觉得很美味
Still very tasty.
# 应该是可以并存的两种口味吧
It's like, the two flavors can live together.
# 这个芋头饼确实是很多人来排队
There're quite many people lining up for the taro cakes.
# 但是大家对它的
However, speaking of their comments,
# 口味 味道的评价
there are quite different comments on
# 还是很不一样的
the taste of the cakes.
# 我刚才走的时候
When I was leaving the booth,
# 遇到几个骑自行车的年轻人
I met some young bike riders.
# 他说这边排队排什么的 你知道吗
One of them said, "Do you know what these people are lining up for?"
# 另一个人说是芋头饼
Another said it's taro cakes,
# 还说自己吃过 但并没有觉得很好吃
and said they've tried it before but didn't feel anything special about it.
# 这一种食物 可能有几百人
There might be hundreds,
# 甚至几千人吃过
or thousands of people who have tried this food.
# 大家对它的评价肯定也是
So their comments must be like,
# 有好的 有坏的
there are both positive ones and negative ones.
# 不可能一种食物 满足所有人的口味
It's impossible that the same food satisfies
# 所有人的胃口
everyone's taste, or preference.
# （你也可以自己动手做出来）
(You can make it by yourselves)
# 我给大家说一个比较有意思的事情
Let me tell you something interesting.
# 因为我们都是山东人
We are Shandong people,
# 来福建这边 每一顿饭都是吃的米饭
but every meal we had here in Fujian is rice.
# 然后这个
And, you know...
# 牙口可能觉得不合适啊（原字幕没有）
Our teeth are probably not quite used to that.
# 有种想要吃这种坚硬的 韧性的东西磨磨牙
We kind of want something hard and chewy to work our teeth.
# （好久没有吃面食了）
# 今天我们来吃的是芋头饼
(We haven't had anything flour for long)
So today, as we planned taro cakes,
# 我们的小哥说
our buddy said,
# 今天总算可以吃一顿 饼了
"Finally, we can eat some 'bing' cakes (wheat flour cake)."
# 无论如何 它也是饼呀
After all, they are cakes.
# 即使是芋头饼 它也是饼
Even taro cake has the word "cake".
# 没想到 它还是软的
We didn't expect that it's still soft.
# 生活 总是充满了各种惊喜
(Life is always full of surprises)
# 这边还有吗
Anything left here?
# 卖光了
Sold out.
# 这么快吗（嗯）
Is it this fast? (Yeah)
# 阿姨 您一天拿多少个来
Auntie, how many cakes do you bring here everyday?
# 500个
500 cakes.
# 卖完就走？（嗯）
And you leave after sold out. (Yeah)
# 没有买到的顾客前来询问
(Customers checking if it's sold out...)
# 你看前面都是几十个 几十个的买
As you see, those people were buying in dozens.
# 四五十个 四五十个的买
Buying 40 or 50 cakes at a time.
# 所以卖很快 每天都不够卖
So it's sold out very fast. Never had enough to sell on any day.
# 你做多少 都会卖光光
No matter how many you make, they're always sold out.
# 做500个 不到一个小时就卖光
Even I make 500 cakes, sometimes they are sold out in an hour.
# 一天就做这500个 多了也做不出来吧
So you make 500 cakes everyday. Guess that the most you can make?
# 要想做多 要更早起来做
If I want to make more, I need to get up earlier.
# 要早一点起床来做
Got to get up earlier.
# 没了
Sold out.
# 这么快？
Sold out this fast?
# 对 没啦
Yeah, it's sold out.
# 噢 天呐
Oh, my gosh.
# （关注雪鱼探店）
(Subscribe)